Life's greatest adventures begin with a single leap.
Ballerina is a animation, adventure, comedy film directed by Eric Summer.
In 1879 Paris, a young orphan dreams of becoming a ballerina and flees her rural Brittany for Paris, where
she passes for someone else and accedes to the position of pupil at the Grand Opera house.
Félicie Milliner (voice), played by Elle Fanning.
Victor (voice), played by Dane DeHaan.
Odette (voice), played by Carly Rae Jepsen.
Camille Le Haut (voice), played by Maddie Ziegler.
Mustachioed Creep (voice), played by Mel Brooks.
Regine Le Haut (voice), played by Julie Khaner.
Ballerina (titled Leap!
in the United States) is a 2016 3D animated musical adventure comedy film co-directed by Éric
Summer and Éric Warin and written by Summer, Carol Noble and Laurent Zeitoun.
A co-production between Canadian and French companies, the film takes place in 1880s France and follows an orphan girl who
dreams of becoming a ballerina and gets a chance to audition for the celebrated school of the Paris Opera Ballet.
Ballerina stars the voices of Elle Fanning, Dane
DeHaan, Maddie Ziegler and Carly Rae Jepsen.
The film was released in cinemas in France and the United Kingdom on 12 December 2016, followed by releases
in various countries over the following several months, including Canada on 24 February 2017.
The film was released in the United States on 25 August 2017, with the voices of
Nat Wolff (who replaced DeHaan), Kate McKinnon and Mel Brooks added.
Ballerina received generally mixed reviews from critics, but was a box office
success, grossing $109.6 million worldwide against a $30 million budget.
The film explores themes of opera, dance, paris, france, flying, inventor.
The tone is lighthearted.